Register to The David Kraehenbuehl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Writings, Series II
  - Writings by David Kraehenbuehl, II.A
    - Program notes. Symphony of the Hills, July 8, 1985. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Wolf-Ferrari Overture to The Secret of Suzanne. -- Barber Intermezzo from Vanessa. -- Gershwin Selections from Porgy and Bess. -- Griffes The White Peacock, Opus 7, No. 1. -- Wagner Die Meistersinger von Nurnberg Overture. -- Mendelssohn Symphony in A Major, No. 4, Opus 90.
    - Program notes. Symphony of the Hills, July 28, 1985. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Wolf-Ferrari Overture to The Secret of Suzanne. -- Ibert Homage a Mozart. -- Wagner A Siegfried Idyll. -- Brahms Symphony No. 2 in D Major, Opus 73.
    - Program notes. Symphony School of America, July 20, 1983. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Dvorak Symphony No. 7 (No. 2) in D Minor, Opus 70. -- Wagner Liebestod from Tristan and Isolde. -- Piston Suite from the Ballet The Incredible Flutist.
    - Recognizing performance traps / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1983, p. 11-12.
    - [Review] The art of fingering in piano playing, by Julien Musafia / reviewed by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1972, p. 15-16.
    - [Review] George Rochberg: String Quartet, 1952. Ernst Toch: Dedication. Heitor Villa-Lobos: String Quartets, nos. 4, 7, and 12. Ernest Gold: String Quartet no. 1. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Music Library Association Notes, v. 15 (1957-58), p. 147.
    - [Review] The sonatas of Beethoven as he played and taught them, by Kenneth Drake / reviewed by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1973, p. 14.
    - The rhetoric of music / David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - The rhetoric of music / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1982, p. 5-6.
    - Rubato revisited / by David Kraehenbuehl., 10 p; 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      "A Keyboard Arts Publication."
    - Rubato signs?: an unscholarly observation / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1973, p. 4-5.
    - Scholarship and creativity: a challenge of opposites / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      Published in American Music Teacher, Sept.-Oct., 1958, p. 4, 36-37.
    - Some myths about the music of J. S. Bach., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      On verso: The quality of various major and minor keys as described by Johann Mattheson in 1713, 1 p.
    - Some recommendations regarding Beethoven editions / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1973, p. 5.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts, Summer 1982, p. 8.
    - The sound of silence / by David Kraehenbuehl., 7 p.; 22 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, April 1982, p. 11-17.
    - Student, teach thyself! / David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, July 1981, p. 13-16.
    - The subject of Bach / David Kraehenbuehl., 8 p.; 22 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, March 1981, p. 3-11.
    - Taking the abstract out of abstract music [lecture notes], 22 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - A teacher's guide to some Scarlatti sonatas / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Teaching taste [lecture notes], 10 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Technic lesson plans. -- c.1977 by the National Keyboard Arts Associates., 46 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      By David Kraehenbuehl? [DK written in ink on title page]
      2 copies, on title page of one copy: Correction copy, 1-50.
      see also: Writings by Others. Whalen, Anita. Keyboard Arts Technic Routines.
    - Technic lesson plans: lessons 51-100. -- c.1977 by the National Keyboard Arts Associates., 50 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Technic: what is it? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1987, p. 13-15.
    - There is only one practice plan for advanced repertoire / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1976, p. 5-7.
    - There is only one practice plan for advanced repertoire (part II) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1976, p. 10-12.
    - There is only one practice plan for advanced repertoire (conclusion) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1977, p. 15-16.
    - Toward a general theory of music / by David Kraehenbuehl., 18 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Typescript, lacks p. 18.
      2 copies, 1 is a photocopy [complete]
    - Tuning project [notes], 32 p.; 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Some notes and computer printouts appear to be the work of Christopher Light.
    - Twelve-tone techniques [lecture notes] (Box 8, Folder 132)
      8 p.; 28 cm
    - The upper arm: source of rhythmic control / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p.; 22 cm. (Box 8, Folder 133)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, November 1981, p. 3-8.
    - Using numbers to represent the experience of sound., 7 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 133)
      Typescript, annotations in pencil.
    - What happened to legato? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 134)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1986, p. 5-6.
    - What time is it? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 134)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1984, p. 5-6.
    - Which Bach edition should I use? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 134)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1972, p. 5.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts, May 1982, p. 10-11.
    - Why not transcriptions? / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p.; 22 cm. (Box 8, Folder 134)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, December 1980, p. 2-7.
    - Yes, we can kill two birds with one stone / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 134)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1976, p. 6-7.
    - [Untitled essay on polytonality and twelve-tone theory], 16 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 135)
      Introduction (2 p.) -- Polytonal chords (6 p.) -- [twelve-tone technique] (8 p.)
  - Writings by Others, II.B
    - Prayers from the Ark / by Carmen Bernos de Gasztold; translated from the French and with a forward and epilogue by Rumer Godden; illustrations by Jean Primrose. -- New York: The Viking Press, 1962., Bernos de Gasztold, Carmen (Box 8, Folder 136)
      Inscribed: "To David and Marie, 1964, with great affection, Blanche Porto."
    - Writings by Others, Braden, Martha
      see: Keyboard Companion.
    - Remembering David Kraehenbuehl., Burkhart, Charles (Charles L.); 10 p.; 23 cm. (Box 8, Folder 137)
      In Journal of Music Theory, v.41, no. 2 (Fall 1997), pp. 183-192.
      Entire issue.
    - [Libretto for an opera], Christophe, François; 14 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 138)
      Typescript, annotations and corrections in pencil and colored pencil.
      Opening section set by David Kraehenbuehl as Ein Traum eines Harlekins.
    - Writings by Others, Chronister, Richard
    - Writings by Others, Connors, Nancy M.
    - [Lecture notes], Coons, Edward; 15 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 139)
      [Lecture notes]
    - Dialogue in three parts for Mary Magdalen., 10 p.; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 140)
      Typescript.
      Possibly by David Kraehenbuehl?
    - Collected poems, 1909-1935 / T. S. Eliot. -- New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, c.1930., Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965 (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Pencil annotations by David Kraehenbuehl, pp. 109-121, 213-220.
      Collected poems, 1909-1935 / T. S. Eliot. -- New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, c.1930.
    - Four quartets / T. S. Eliot. -- New York: Harcourt, Brace and company, c.1943., Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965 (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Signed on flyleaf: Marie Marek Kraehenbuehl.
      Four quartets / T. S. Eliot. -- New York: Harcourt, Brace and company, c.1943.
    - God's trombones: seven Negro sermons in verse. / James Weldon Johnson; drawings by Aaron Douglas; lettering by C. B. Falls. -- New York: Penguin Books, 1990., Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938 (Box 9, Folder 142)
      "Reprint of the 1969 ed."
      God's trombones: seven Negro sermons in verse. / James Weldon Johnson; drawings by Aaron Douglas; lettering by C. B. Falls. -- New York: Penguin Books, 1990.
    - Keyboard Arts Associates Newsletter, Winter 1989. (Box 9, Folder 143)
      "David Kraehenbuehl to retire." (1 p.)
      "Workshop banquet to honor David Kraehenbuehl." (1 p.)
    - Keyboard Companion, v.8, no. 2 (Summer 1997), p. 17-19. (Box 9, Folder 143)
      Chronister, Richard. "David Kraehenbuehl, 1923-1997."
      Braden, Martha, and Nancy M. Connors. "David Kraehenbuehl, 73, American composer, founder of Yale journal."
      Whalen, Anita. "A Tribute to David Kraehenbuehl."
    - Reprint of above, labeled v.8, no. 4 (Winter 1997) (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - There is something ancient here: poems / by Ellen Kort. Bruce: Woelfinger Press, 1986., Kort, Ellen, 1936-; 49 p.; 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 144)
      With biographical flyer.
      There is something ancient here: poems / by Ellen Kort. Bruce: Woelfinger Press, 1986.
    - On the generation of Greek modes and Arabic quartertones., Light, Christopher U.; 10 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 145)
      On the generation of Greek modes and Arabic quartertones.
    - The theory of quartertone systems., Light, Christopher U.; 17 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 145)
      "Draft, 2/16/87"
    - Rethinking contemporary music theory., McCreless, Patrick; 21 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 146)
      Photocopy, annotations in ink [in the hand of Charles Burkhart?]
      Published in Keeping Score: Music, Disciplinarity, Culture, edited by David Schwartz, Anahid Kassabian, and Lawrence Siegel. (Charlottesville: University Press of Virginia, 1997), pp. 13-53.
    - Seven archaic images / by Thomas Merton., Merton, Thomas; 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 147)
      Typescript and photocopy of typescript.
      3 copies, one annotated in colored pencil.
    - Drumfire in letters, poetry, and prose / Goff Owen [Sr.]; transcribed and interpreted by Louise R. Ritenour; ed. by Goff Owen, Jr. -- c.1985 by Goff Owen, Jr., Owen, Goff; 123 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 148)
      Photocopy of typescript, annotations in pencil by David Kraehenbuehl.
      Inscribed: To David Kraehenbuehl, with best regards, Goff Owen, Jr. 3/21/85
      Another copy, gift of Goff Owen, Jr.
    - Cents Values of Intervals, Partch, Harry, 1901-1974; 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 149)
      From: Genesis of a Music (Madison: University of Wisconsin Press, 1949), pp. 333-335.
    - View from the Podium., Rusterholz, Paul; 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 150)
      In Take Note: The Newsletter of the La Crosse Chamber Chorale.
    - Keyboard Arts technic routines: adaptation of lesson plans for college level. -- February 8, 1981 [notes], Whalen, Anita; 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 151)
      With 3 pads of Technic Assignments: 26-50, 51-73, 75-100.
      see also: [David Kraehenbuehl]. Technic Lesson Plans.
    - Writings by Others, Whalen, Anita
      see also: Keyboard Companion.
    - [Fisherman and his soul], Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900; 29 p.; 28 cm. (Box 9, Folder 152)
      Annotations: vertical bars were in red ink, all others in pencil.
      From program: Based on an ancient Japanese fairytale as related by Oscar Wilde.
- Correspondence, Series III
  - Family correspondence, 1920s & 1930s; 19 pages. (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Family correspondence, 1940s; 203 pages. (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - Family correspondence, 1970s; 35 pages. (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Associated Music Publishers, 1952, 1954; 3 pages. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Bird, Nathalie, 1954; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Blackmore, Bryon, 1989; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Blair, David H., 1964; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1958; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Braden, Martha, 1989-1995; 8 pages. (Box 9, Folder 156)
    (includes timings, curriculum vitae, and program notes)
  - Bronson, Lyn, 1993; 7 pages. (Box 9, Folder 156)
    (includes biographical entry and program)
  - Buis, Johann S., 1989; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Burkhart, Charles, n.d.; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 156)
    from Richmond Browne
  - Campbell, Aurelia, 1986; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Cohen, Sol, 1942; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Coons, Edgar ("Ted"), from Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1997; 4 pages. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Demske, Thomas R.
    see: Yale University. Department of Music
  - Dissmore, Larry, 1988; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Drexler, David.
    see: Wisconsin Alliance for Composers. Madison Chapter.
  - Donohue, Richard Wm., 1993; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Dropkin, V. H., 1942; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Engebreth, Aaron, to Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1997; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Erftenbeck, Deborah, to Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1997; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Fletcher, Stanley, 1951-87; 4 pages. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - French, Richard F.
    see: Associated Music Publishers
  - Frye, Christopher, to Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1997; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Furck, Mary Ann, 1989; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Gilliland, Norman, 1994; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Goss, Robert, 1966; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Haener, Dorothy N., 1954; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Hays, Alfreda R., 1966; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Heiden, Bernhard and Lola, 1954-55; 3 pages. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Hill, William G., 1949; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Hillis, Margaret, from Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1997; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Hindemith, Paul and Gertrude, 1947-1952; 8 pages. (Box 9, Folder 159)
    (2 letters and 3 Christmas cards, all written by Gertrude Hindemith)
    (photocopies in David Kraehenbuehl reference file in the Music Library)
  - Italiano, Frank, 1975; 3 pages. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Jackson, Gus E., 1953; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - James, Sallyrae and Sallyann Keeffe, [1989]; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Journal of Music Theory
    see: Yale University. Department of Music.
  - Kohner, Gertrude S., 1988; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Kort, Ellen, 1989; 7 pages. (Box 9, Folder 160)
    (includes typescript of 4 poems)
  - David Kraehenbuehl to Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1953; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Knodle, Dick, 1942; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Kratz, Mrs. A. P. and Mrs. R. B. Wilhelm, 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Lanner, Max, to Bruce Simonds, 1953; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Leonhardt, Gustav, 1950, n.d.; 4 pages. (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Light, Christopher U., 1987-1996; 28 pages. (Box 9, Folder 161)
  - Lohr, Ina, 1952-54; 7 pages. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Lundblad, Harry A., 1955; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Mann, Carol F., 1989; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Mahr, Jeanne, 1994; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Martirano, Dorothy, 1991; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Morehouse, Thomas L., 1987; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Müller, Hannelore, 1950; 2 pages. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Oliver, Lois F., 1993; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Osborn, James M., 1958; 1 page. (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Owen, Goff, Jr., 1983-1999; 31 pages. (Box 9, Folder 163)
    (includes correspondence with Richmond Browne, Francis F. Slade, Frank Tirro, and Marie Kraehenbuehl.)
    (primarily the gift of Goff Owen, Jr.)
  - Pannebaker, Denise.
    see: White Heron Chorale
  - Perry, Thomas D.
    see: Boston Symphony Orchestra
  - Pauly, Elizabeth, n.d.; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Pond, Francis, 1953; 4 pages. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Rice, Barbara, 1989; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Sacher, Paul., 1954; 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Satyendra, Ramon.
  - Slade, Frances F., to Marie Kraehenbuehl, [June, 1997]; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 164)
    see also: Owen, Goff, Jr.
  - Slade, John, 1982; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Spack, Edith, 1949; 3 pages. (Box 10, Folder 164)
  - Tirro, Frank
    see: Owen, Goff, Jr.
  - University of Illinois. College of Fine and Applied Arts, 1949; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Watkins, Armin., 1958-1960; 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - White Heron Chorale, 1989; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Wiley, Flossie, 1937; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel, 1954; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Wisconsin Alliance for Composers. Madison Chapter., 1997; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Yale University, 1958-1959; 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Yale University. Department of Music, 1995; 3 pages. (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Unidentified, 1985; 1 page. (Box 10, Folder 166)
    (Marie Kraehenbuehl to various family members)
  - Get-well cards, 1989; 42 pages. (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Thank you card from David Kraehenbuehl & Marie Kraehenbuehl, 1989; 2 pages. (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Typed excerpts from sympathy cards, 3 pages. (Box 10, Folder 168)
- Programs and Publicity, Series IV
  - 1920s - 1930s (Box 10, Folder 169)
  - 1940s (Box 10, Folder 170)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - 1960s (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - 1970s (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 176)
  - 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 177)
  - 1990s (Box 11, Folder 178)
  - undated and miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 179)
- Clippings and Scrapbooks, Series V
  - Clippings, V.A
    - 1930s (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - 1940s (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - 1980s (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - 1990s (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - undated (Box 11, Folder 187)
  - Scrapbooks, V.B
    Note: Reel 1926a is shelved with the microfilm collections in the Music Library.
    - Scrapbook 1
    - Scrapbook 2
    - Scrapbook 3
- Photographs, Series VI
  - Photos of David Kraehenbuehl
    - 1923, Christmas, 1-13 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - 1924, 14-16 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - 1924, Christmas, 17-36 (Box 12, Folder 189)
      [2 copies of each]
    - 1927, 37 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - 1931, June [silhouettes], 38-39 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1930s, 40, 40a (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1939, June, high school graduation, 41-42 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1940, 43 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1943-1946, US. Army, 44-46 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1947-1949, Connecticut, 47-61 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1949-1950, Europe, 62-71 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - 1950s, 72-73 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - 1960s, 74-75 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - 1984, 76 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - 1986 [gift of Goff Owen, Jr.], 77a-77d (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - 1993 [gift of Goff Owen, Jr.], 77e (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - 1996, 78-79 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - gravesite, 1999; 80 (Box 12, Folder 191)
  - Photos of Marie Kraehenbuehl
    - 1947-1949, Connecticut, 81-90 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - 1949-1950, Europe, 91 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - 1996, 92 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - Photos of David and Marie Kraehenbuehl
    - 1947, wedding, 93-94 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - 1947, 95 (Box 12, Folder 192)
      [2 copies]
    - 1947-1949, Connecticut, 96-104 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - 1970s, 105 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - 1980s, 106-107 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - Photos of David Kraehenbuehl and 1 other person
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Kathryn Kraehenbuehl, 108 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Carol Jean Kraehenbuehl, 109-113 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and various Army, 114-117 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Frank Costanzo, 1953; 117a-117d (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and George Hunter, 118 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Goff Owen, Jr., 1986; 118a (Box 12, Folder 193)
      [gift of Goff Owen, Jr.]
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Nancy Pelliccia, 118b (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and Leonard Sarason, 1949; 118c (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - David Kraehenbuehl and unidentified, 118d (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - Photos of Marie Kraehenbuehl and 1 other person
    - Marie Kraehenbuehl and Doris Bullock, 119 (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - Photos of David Kraehenbuehl and several others
    - Forestry School, Urbana, and Taylor's Co-op Playground, 1930; 120-131 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Elizabeth Gonnoway, Bill Walker, ca. 1939; 132 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Morgan County, Tennessee, 1941; 133 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - U.S. Army, 1943-1946; 134-135 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, MK, Mr. & Mrs. DeLarge, others, 1948; 136-137 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Europe, 1949-1950; 137a (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Warren Stannard, Helen Stannard, 137b (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Frank Costanzo, Ferenc Molnar, Colorado College, 1953; 137c-137g (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, MK, Vlosta Marek, Joseph Marek, others, 138-140 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Robert Abelson, Harry Lundblad, Mrs. Samuel Mills, Inge Venus, 1975; 141 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, LAMTA meeting, 142 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Frank Tirro, Yale School of Music alumni meeting, 1983; 143 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Frances Slade, et. al., Princeton, 1986; 143a (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - David Kraehenbuehl, Goff Owen, Jr., Larry Kettelkamp, et. al., Princeton, 1986; 143b (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Keyboard Arts Teaching Techniques, Portland, Chicago, New York, Tulsa, 1986; 144 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      [photo collage]
    - David Kraehenbuehl and family members, 1993; 144a (Box 12, Folder 194)
  - Photos of Others
    - Kathryn Lohr Kraehenbuehl, 145-148 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      [mother]
    - John Otto Kraehenbuehl, 149-151 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      [father]
    - Kathryn and John Otto Kraehenbuehl, 152-155 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Agnes and Oscar Kraehenbuehl, 156-157 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      [aunt and uncle]
    - Carol Jean Kraehenbuehl, 158-159 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      [sister]
    - Carol Jean and John Otto Kraehenbuehl, 160-161 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Roger Kraehenbuehl, 162 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - George and Doris Bullock, 163-164a (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - George and Vivian Hunter and family, 165-168 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Harold Mandelkorn, 169-170 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Champaign Urbana Civic Symphony Orchestra, 1941; 171 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - 12 women singing in Sprague Hall, 1954, 172 (Box 12, Folder 196)
      [list laid in]
    - Princeton Pro Musica premiere of Drumfire, 1986; 172a (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - University High School 50th class reunion, 1989; 173 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - various ancestors and family members - color photocopies of old photographs, 174-184 (Box 12, Folder 197)
  - Travel photos and locations
    - University of Illinois [?], 185-186 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Asia, 1945-1946; 187-221 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Return from Army, 1946; 222-225 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Connecticut and New York, 1947-1969; 226-290 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Europe, 1949-1950; 291-391 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Hand-colored cartoon figures from Carnival in Basel, 392-394 (Box 12, Folder 199)
- Biographical Materials, Series VII
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 13, Folder 200)
    [3 versions: 1 p., 13 pp., 12 pp]
  - "Babyhood" diary kept by Kathryn Kraehenbuehl (Box 13, Folder 201)
  - High School (Box 13, Folder 202)
    Student work, teachers' reports, play scripts
  - High School (Box 13, Folder 203)
    Diary kept by David Kraehenbuehl, June 1937-June 1938